(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T21:44:50.751453",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
忘れられないで
Don't forget me,
ダンス・ザ・ビート
dance the beat,
君のことが
I've always loved
ずっと好きさ
everything about you!
忘れられないで
Don't forget me,
ダンス・ザ・ビート
dance the beat,
どこに行っても
no matter where I go,
君が好きさ
I still love you!
もう一度
Once more,
キャッチ・アンド・ジャンプ
catch and jump!
誰よりも上手いね
You're better than anyone,
ベイビー
baby!
道詰めて
Close the distance,
もっと近く
come closer!
ギルティ・パーティ
The guilty party
終わんないよヘイ
never ends, hey!
心よキラキラ
Make my heart sparkle and shine,
弾けて上手く
burst out and get it right!
盛り上がろう刻みたいよ
Let's get hyped, I want to carve it in,
次去る時捕まえて
catch me before I leave next time,
永遠なんて
forever...
言わないけど今はダンス
I won't say it, but I'm dancing right now!
やっぱり君は最高のパートナー
After all, you're the ultimate partner!
キラキラはずむなら一緒なら何とかかなりそう
If it sparkles and bounces, if we're together, we can manage somehow!
だから…
That's why...
夢だけ見てて
Keep dreaming only,
ダンス・ザ・ビート
dance the beat!
君と踊って
Dancing with you,
いたいだけさ
I just want to stay!
夢だけ見てて
Keep dreaming only,
ダンス・ザ・ビート
dance the beat!
熱いままの
With this burning passion,
胸が痛いね
my heart aches so much!
もう一度
Once more,
キャッチ・アンド・ジャンプ
catch and jump!
誰よりも
Better than anyone,
うまいねベイビー
you're good, baby!
道詰めて
Close the distance,
もっと近く
come closer!
ギルティ・パーティ終わんないよヘイ
The guilty party never ends, hey!
打ち上がろう
Let's launch up,
頑張ったことが
everything we worked hard for...
気恥ずかしいんだすべてが役に立つ日が来るってさ
It's all so embarrassing, but the day will come when it all comes in handy!
信じてダンス・ダンス
Believe in it, dance, dance!
周りながら永遠に光の色を変えるミラーボール
Revolving forever, the mirror ball changes the color of light!
眩し目で夜でも朝でもない世界でユーアンドアイダンス・ダンス
In a dazzling world that is neither night nor morning, You & I dance, dance!
そうだよ君は最高のパートナー
That's right, you're the ultimate partner!
弾けてはずむなら一緒にいたいって願いは同じ
If it bursts and bounces, our wish to stay together is the same!
カモンパーティ！
Come on, party!
青い風に吹かれて
Blown by the blue wind,
耳を澄ます海の詩
I listen closely to the song of the waves.
肩寄せ合い見つめていた
Shoulder to shoulder, gazing at each other,
果てなき空の永遠
The eternity of the endless sky.
“好き”が溢れて 切なく湿った身体
Overflowing with "I love you," my body damp with tender sorrow,
あなたに伝えたいよ close to me
I want to tell you, close to me.
hold me tight いつまでも…
Hold me tight, forever...
hey yeah 遥かなる grand blue
Hey yeah, the distant grand blue,
baby 側に入らせて
Baby, let me stay by your side.
会いたい 明日もあさっても あなたに触れていたい
I want to see you, tomorrow and the day after, I want to touch you.
hey yeah 永遠なる grand blue
Hey yeah, the eternal grand blue,
baby 素直に言える 少し照れるけれども
Baby, I can say it honestly, even though I feel a little shy,
すごく 愛しくて 涙が流れて来る
I love you so much, tears begin to fall.
あらためまして、こんねね！
Good evening once again, it's Con-Nene!
こんねねー！よー！
Con-Nene! Yay!
ほら、みんなクリスマスライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to the Christmas live!
そして今日はねの、えっと、1時間のライブに一緒に、あ、1時間やってもらうことになりました。
And today, Nene's... um, we'll be doing a one-hour live together—ah, having you do one hour with us!
えっ、水ちゃん！？
Eh, Suichan!?
はい、水星のこと現われたスターの儀式アイドル、一番星の星街水星です。よろしくお願いします！
Yes, I am Hoshimachi Suisei, the star-born ritual idol of Hoshimachi. Nice to meet you!
そしてトワ先輩！
And Towa-senpai!
ほら、夜2千の、とかみとわです！
Hello, I'm Tokoyami Towa!
そして、ほらライブごきげんうれじタント、アイドル一番星のももすずねねでーす！
And the energetic and happy-go-lucky idol of the top star, Momosuzu Nene!
え、ヘッドヘッドじゃねえか！え、最後に重大発表もありますので、よかったら最後まで楽しんでいってください！
Head-head? And finally, there's a big announcement coming, so please enjoy it all the way to the end!
最初どうだった？いや、めっちゃ緊張した！でもね、みんなめっちゃ緊張してた、でしょ？
How was it at first? Man, I was so nervous! But everyone was super nervous too, right?
めっちゃ練習してきたんで今日、みんなはどうだった？どうだった、みんな？みんな、お前たち、どうだ？
We practiced really hard for today, how was it for everyone? How was it, everyone? Everyone, you guys, how was it?
ほら、可愛い可愛いって、みんな。あ、本当？言ってる、言ってる。よかった、すずねね。
Look, everyone's saying "So cute!" Oh really? They are? Good, Suzu-Nene.
え、緊張しちゃう、マジで！いやじゃ、コメントが早すぎて読めないね。ありがとう！
Man, I get so nervous, seriously! The comments are moving way too fast to read. Thank you!
さて、それでは早速ですね、次のパートに移っていきたいと思うんですけど。ここから、なんと！ソロパートでございます！
Now then, let's move right along to the next part. From here, amazingly, it's solo parts!
え、まず誰から歌うのかな？
Eh, who's singing first?
いや、トワだからね。じゃあ、ちょっと乗ってよ、乗ってよ。お前だけだぞ！
Well, because it's Towa. So get into it, get into it. You're the only one!
じゃあ、うちらも、頑張ってね！
Alright, let's do our best too!
分かりました！ということでトップバッターをね、いただきましたソロで！イェーイ！緊張するんですけども、まあ頑張って歌いたいと思います！可愛い曲なんでね、可愛く歌いますので、優しい目で聞いてくれたら嬉しいです！じゃあ、それでは聞いてください、「Lunch with me」！
Understood! So I got the top batter slot for my solo! Yay! I'm nervous, but I'll do my best to sing! It's a cute song, so I'll sing it cutely, I'd be happy if you watched over me with gentle eyes! Alright, then please listen to "Lunch with me"!
遥く起きた朝は なんだかいつもより眠れて
On mornings when I wake up late, I feel sleepier than usual,
昨日の夜 ずっとマンガを読んでたら眠れなくてさ
I stayed up late last night reading manga and couldn't fall asleep.
今頃そっち はどこで何をしてるかななんて
Wondering what you might be doing right about now and where you are,
考えてたら 心がふわっと軽くなるんだ
As I think about it, my heart feels light and fluffy.
これは内緒なんだけど 昨日読んだマンガの
This is just between us, but the main character of the manga I read yesterday,
主人公に 君がちょっと似てたんだよ
Was a little bit like you, you know.
ねえ お昼一緒にお昼食べよう
Hey, let's have lunch together, let's eat lunch!
ちょっとだけ同じ気持ち共有したくて
Sharing the same feeling for just a bit...
そうキラキラキラキラキラキラだけども
So even if it's glittering all alone,
そんな特別なことなくても
It's fine, isn't it?
いつものキミでいいんだよ
It's fine to just be your usual self.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together.
ステキなずっとは
Even though for a long time now
言えない地味な日々だけどさ
It's been a quiet, ordinary daily life.
なんだろう最近上手く少しキラキラなんだ
Why do I suddenly feel a bit sparkly?
どんなに直截に気の利いたことあっても
No matter how straightforwardly things go,
キミに会えると元にもう照れちゃってさぁ
If I meet you, I'll just get all shy!
ねぇキラキラキラキラキラキラ一緒に
Let's shine together!
跳ぼう一人よりきっと楽しくなるから
Because going it alone will surely be more fun!
そうキラキラキラキラキラキラだけども
So even if it's glittering all alone,
そんな特別なことなくても ないから
There's no strange things to worry about, right?
変なコト考えないでよ まぁ 別にいいけど
Well, it doesn't really matter,
知ってるかな
I bet you know.
キミがくれることは一つ一つ
There's one, only one thing you give me.
嬉しくなったり楽しくなったり不思議なパワーを感じる
I can feel this strange power of getting happy and having fun!
てことさ
That's right!
ねぇキラキラキラキラキラキラ一緒に跳ぼう
Let's shine together, let's jump!
ちょっとだけ同じ気持ち共有したくて
Sharing the same feeling for just a bit...
そうキラキラキラキラキラキラだけども
So even if it's glittering all alone,
そんな特別なことなくても
It's fine, isn't it?
いつでもキミがいいんだよ
It's fine to just be your usual self anytime.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together.
風に吹かれて 誰も気づかないように
Blown away by the wind, unnoticed by anyone,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
In a monochrome world where I can't tell things apart.
色を足しても 何も見えなくて
Even if I add colors, I can't see anything at all,
まるで私は 息を止めていた
As if I had been holding my breath.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は
It's fine now, even if it's far away, I want to make it happen.
こんな世界 想いも 抱きしめていた いのに
I wanted to embrace even this kind of world and my thoughts.
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味は
The meaning of continuing to be on the canvas of dreams
この胸に 輝いている ストーリー
Is a story shining right in this chest.
与えることに 意味などないけど
There's no real meaning in giving things,
拾い集めた カケラ失うの？
Are we losing the fragments we picked up?
そして夜は その冷たさを 溶かして 手を伸ばし
And then, the night... melting that coldness, I reached out my hand.
風に吹かれて 誰も気づかぬように
Blown by the wind, so that no one would notice,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
an indistinguishable monochrome world.
色を足しても 何も見えなくて
Even adding colors, nothing was in sight,
まるで私たちは 息を止めていた
as if we were holding our breath.
もういいよ 遠くても
It's fine now, even if it's far away,
叶えたい 私は
I want to make it come true.
こんな世界 想いも抱きしめていたいのに
Even though I want to embrace my feelings in this world...
そして夜は その冷たさを
And the night melts away
溶かして 手を伸ばした
that coldness and reached out its hand.
もういいの 遠くても
It's fine now, even if it's far away,
届けたい 私の
I want to reach it,
こんな世界 想いも言葉で包んで
wrapping the feelings of this world in words.
夢のキャンバスに 色を足してゆく
Adding colors to the canvas of dreams,
この胸に 今輝いて
shining now in this heart.
強くななくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong,
壊れかけててもいい
it's okay to be on the verge of breaking.
この心は 永遠に羽ばたいて
This heart will soar forever,
響くように 塗り替えていく
repainting so that it echoes.
Palette
※クリスマス3Dライブ※ GHOST
[Christmas 3D Live] GHOST
パッと弾けた感情に
To emotions that burst in a flash,
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my days making excuses.
葛藤も知らない街明かり
City lights that don't even know conflict,
君だけだって嘘をついた
I lied, saying it was only you.
信じたくもないままで踊っている
Dancing without even wanting to believe it,
示すために続き続けた言葉
words I kept repeating just to show the way.
見えないの 僕が僕のこの声が聴こえている?
Can't you see? Can you hear this voice of mine?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy as it is,
せめて声を枯らそう 必死に縋ってでもずっと証明を
at least I'll make my voice hoarse, clinging desperately to proof.
ねえ GHOST みたいだ
Hey, I'm just like a ghost.
散々恨んだ明るさと 意味ありげに伸びていく影
The brightness I resented so much, and shadows stretching meaningfully.
淡々と過ぎた一粒の 君の言葉で泣きたくなった
A single moment passed indifferently, your words made me want to cry.
大切にしたいものがこぼれていく 示すままに繋がり続けたい言葉
What I wanted to hold dear is spilling out, words I wanted to keep connecting.
見えているの 僕が僕のこの声が届いている?
Can you see? Is this voice of mine reaching you?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy as it is.
だから叫んで足掻いて 足のままに走って ねえ気付いて
So I'll shout and struggle, running wherever my feet take me, hey, notice me.
教えて答えは こんな私の心までバカにしないで
Tell me the answer, don't make a mockery of even my heart.
灰色街が笑っている 足取りも重くなる
The gray streets are laughing, my steps grow heavy.
声を枯らして 叫んで足掻いて 足のままに走り続けて
Straining my voice, shouting and struggling, running on wherever my feet lead,
変わらないように諦めないように 繋がり続けるだけだ
so as not to change, not to give up, just keeping the connection alive.
見つけてよ 僕が僕のこの声が聴こえている?
Find me! Can you hear this voice of mine?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy as it is.
せめて声を枯らそう 必死に縋ってでもずっと証明を
At least I'll strain my voice hoarse, clinging on desperately for proof.
ねえ GHOST みたいだ
Hey, I'm just like a ghost.
裸のまま走って
Running barefoot.
ねぇねぇねぇ。
Hey, hey, hey.
気づいて
Notice me,
教えてよ
tell me,
答えは
what's the answer?
こんな私の心までバカにしないで
Don't make fun of even my feelings like this.
一方通行のメンションです
It's a one-way mention.
灰色の街が笑ってるよ
The gray city is laughing,
足取りも重くなる
and my steps grow heavy.
声をからして叫んであがいて 果たして走り続けて
Losing my voice, shouting and struggling, I keep running.
変わらないように 諦めないように
So I won't change, so I won't give up,
連ね続けるだけだ
I just keep stringing them along.
見つけてよ僕を
Find me,
僕のこの声が聞こえてる？
can you hear this voice of mine?
残虐に佇むシルエットすらも
Even the brutally standing silhouette
透明できっと不格好だけれどでも
is transparent and surely clumsy, but even so,
せめて声をからそう 必死にしがみついても
let's at least lose our voices, clinging on desperately,
ずっと正面を向いて ねぇゴーストみたいだ
always facing forward. Hey, it's like a ghost.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、じゃあ二人おいで！
Okay, come on over, you two!
あ、こっちでいいか。ここ？
Oh, over here is fine? Here?
ていうわけで、ソロパートを聞きいただきました！
And with that, you've heard our solo parts!
イェーイ！聞いていただきました！
Yay! You heard them!
え、待ってちょっとここさ、言いたいんだけど、ソロパートあるよって話をさ、あの、そのライブが決まってあったじゃん。
Wait, hold on, I want to talk about this. When the live concert was decided, we talked about having solo parts.
で、その時に、え、こ、シャッフル、決めたのトワなんです。天才！当たってました！天才だよ！当たったじゃんトワが。
And at that time, Towa was the one who decided the shuffle. Genius! You hit the spot! You're a genius! Towa got it right.
いや、そう、なんか、ソロって言ったらなんかいろんな振り幅があるけど、ほら、せっかくみんな折り曲持ってるから、それをさ、シャッフルしないかっていう提案をして、お二人がいいよって、本当に良かったよ。
Well, yeah. When we said solos, there's a lot of variety, but since everyone has their own original songs, I suggested shuffling them. You two said yes, and it really turned out great.
めっちゃ緊張した。
I was so nervous.
え、実際、えっと、ランチタイムねねの曲をトワが歌って、
Actually, um, Towa sang Nene's song 'Lunch Time Rendezvous',
で、トワの曲パレットをすいちゃんが歌って、すいちゃんの曲ゴーストをねねが歌うたいました。
Suisei sang Towa's song 'Palette', and Nene sang Suisei's song 'Ghost'.
え、みんなどうだった？歌ってみて。
How was it for everyone, singing them?
いや、まず、じゃあトワから言うね、一番最初の。い、まず、あの、ちょっと、大丈夫かなっていう、なにがなにが？
Well, first, I'll go first, right at the start. Um, first, I was worried like, 'Will I be okay?' — What, what?
トワがランチタイムねね歌っていいのかなっていう不安はあってんけど、でも、ー、キュート、キュート、キュート、キュート、キュート、キュート！
I was worried if it was okay for me to sing 'Lunch Time Rendezvous', but—cute, cute, cute, cute, cute, cute!
でね、めちゃっ、ちょっと、可愛いを意識して歌ってみたんだよ。いや、可愛いかったよ。全然踊りも、え、踊りの可愛さと歌のちょっと、ギャップで、まあ可愛い、可愛いよ！
So, you know, I tried to keep 'cute' in mind while singing. — It was totally cute! Even the dance—the gap between the cute dance and the song... well, it was cute!
ほら、TMティ、TMティ、TMティ、TMティって言われてた。
See, people were calling it 'TM-T', 'TM-T'.
じゃあ、はい、すいちゃん、トワのパレット。すいちゃんはトワの曲歌いました。トワの曲、とーっても難しいね！
Next, yes, Suisei. Towa's 'Palette'. Suisei sang Towa's song. Towa's song is sooo difficult!
え、待って、笑顔が怖い。なんですか、この難しさ。
Wait, your smile is terrifying. What is this difficulty?!
最高に水星の顔してそれ。でも、めっちゃかっこよくって、でもさ、しょっぱなからめっちゃ低いの。「風邪に吹かれて」つって。めっちゃ低くて、で、サビが、あの、もういいよつって。
That's the ultimate Suisei face right there. But it was super cool, and from the very beginning it was so low—'Fukaze ni fukarete'. It was super low, and then the chorus was like, 'Mou ii yo'.
おお、確か、確か、でもうまかったよ。本当？なんかトワが言うのもあれなんだけど、でももう、ゆずり受けちゃった。
Oh, true, true. But you did great! Really? Well, it's not really my place to say, but you pulled it off.
で、パレットの、その、置いてくださいって言われて、おいてはトワのコーラス入りで、
And for 'Palette', I was told to 'please leave it', and it included Towa's chorus!
そうそうそうそう。でも、ランチタイムねねもね、そのねねねのコーラスが入ってて、ゴーストもすいちゃんのコーラスが入ってて、みんなでそう。
That's right, that's right. But 'Lunch Time Rendezvous' had Nene's chorus, 'Ghost' had Suisei's chorus—everyone was linked like that.
なんか、なん、何が上なんだ。はい、そんな感じで、えー、ねねはどうでしたか？
What's on top? Anyway, with that, um, Nene, how was it for you?
いや、あのね、すいちゃんのね、歌を歌うのね、なんかすごいプレッシャーが、わかるよ、わかるよ！
Well, you know, singing Suisei's song... there was so much pressure—I know, I totally know!
早かった！
That was fast!
そんなことない、そんなことない
No way, no way!
全然そんなことないよ
Not at all!
なんかこう、あのクリアな……
Like, you know, clear...
すいちゃんがスリガラスだとしたら、ねねはもう透明ガラスだからさ！
If Suisei-chan is frosted glass, Nene is transparent glass!
例えばすごいクリアな、ゴーストですごいよかったと思う。
For example, a super clear ghost, I think it was great.
おおー、よかった！
Ohh, great!
えいちゃん、この後なんですけど、ちょっと進行下手で申し訳ないんですけど。
Ei-chan... after this, though, I'm sorry for being a bit clumsy with the pacing, but...
ここからですね、なんと2人ずつのデュエットパートに映っていきたいと思います！えいえい！えい！
From here, we're going to move into duet parts with pairs of two! Yay! Yay! Yay!
じゃあね、まずねえと……誰？
Well then, first, Nene and... who?
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽい！あいこでしょ！
Rock, paper, scissors, rock, paper, scissors! Aiko desho!
とわ！
Towa!
あ、とわちゃんだ！いってらっしゃーい！バイバイン！
Ah, it's Towa-chan! Have fun! Bye-bye!
はい、じゃあそれでは、さっそく行きましょう！デュエットパート1曲目、それでは聞いてください！せーの！
Okay, then let's get right into it! Duet part song 1, please listen! Ready, set!
ラッキー！
Lucky!
さあ眠眠打破 昼夜逆転 VOX AC30W
So, time to wake up, day-night reversal, VOX AC30W
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンド仲間にヤッホー
A suburban boy carrying a Telecaster saying hi to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード
Part-time job is in gloomy mode
タイバンにはアットフィールド
At the live house, an outfield
ヒトミシリ宣言で逃げるギークボーイ
A geek boy running away with a social anxiety declaration
ユーテオボッチャお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も
Hey you rich boy, rich girl, money and talent too
ナマジックあるだけヤッカヤンでヤンス
Just having some raw magic, acting all jealous
boys be ambitious
like this old man
長い前髪 キミ誰の信者 信者 信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you? Follower, follower!
勘違いすんな狂騒はお前だ
Make no mistake, the madness is you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
鳴り響くエレクトリックギターはどうさ
How's the echoing electric guitar?
さあキミのすべてを裸にしてみせろよ
Come on, strip bare everything about you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール 死んじまいな寝言
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll, stop talking in your sleep and drop dead!
死にたかないのはお互様
Neither of us wants to die, we're in the same boat!
さあ日進月歩いい曲書いてる動悸ふえてる
Come on, making steady progress, writing good songs, palpitations increasing
知名度あるけど人気はそんなにないから色々大変ですね
We have some fame, but not that much popularity, so it's quite tough
はっきり言うなよ匿名アイコン はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
Don't spell it out, anonymous icon! Don't clearly show your real-life icon!
賢くあざとくやったって10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
Acting smart and sly, in 10 years your makeup will wear off anyway!
boys be ambitious
like this old man
息を抜くためだけメロテとセルフィー セルフィー セルフィー
Just to catch a breath, melodies and selfies, selfies, selfies!
死ぬんじゃねぇぞお互いにな
Don't you dare die on me, we're in this together!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
滑らないラブソングでもいいにどうせ君のすべては裸出して見せろよ
Even a fail-proof love song is fine, strip bare everything about you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール 死んじまいな寝言
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll, stop talking in your sleep and drop dead!
打ち抜いてみせろよ
Shoot right through it!
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
You can't be satisfied by just blurring the lines
泥まみれ滑走路のことわアンチフワンチプレッシャーで一杯
Muddy runway, anti-fans, and full of pressure!
ちぎれそうな首風邪だってセイラ
Even with a neck on the verge of snapping, sayonara!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
鳴り響くエレクトリックギターはどーすんだ
How's the echoing electric guitar?
さあキミのすべてを裸にしてみせろよ
Come on, strip bare everything about you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n' rock 'n' roll
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ死にたかねぇのはお互様
Don't you dare die, neither of us wants to die!
神様の言うとおり生き抜くためだろ
Just as God says, it's to survive!
袖丈も覚束ない夏の終わり
At the end of summer, with sleeves awkwardly long,
明け方の電車に揺られて
Rocked by the dawn train,
思い出した 懐かしいあの風景
I remembered that nostalgic scenery.
たくさんの遠回りを繰り返して
After taking so many detours,
同じような街並みがただ通り過ぎた
Similar cityscapes simply passed by me.
窓に僕が映って
Reflected in the window,
君は今もあの頃みたいにいるのだろうか
I wonder if you're still living like back then.
ひしゃげて曲がった
Riding around on that dented,
あの自転車で走り回った
bent bicycle,
馬鹿馬鹿しい綱渡り 膝に滲んだ血
Doing foolish tightrope walks, blood on my knees.
今はなんだかひどく虚しい
Right now, it all feels so terribly hollow.
どれだけ背丈が変わろうとも 変わらない
No matter how much our heights may change,
何かがありますように
I hope something remains unchanging.
くだらない面影に励まされ
Encouraged by silly memories,
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, still sing, still sing.
忙しなく街を走るタクシーに
In a taxi rushing through the busy city,
ぼんやりと背負われたまま窓の外を眺める
carried along absentmindedly, I gaze outside.
心から震えたあの瞬間に もう一度出会えたなら
In that moment when my heart trembled, I wish we could meet
忘れることはないんだ
once more. I will never forget it.
君は今もあの頃みたいに居るのだろうか
Are you still living like you did back then?
靴を片方茂みに落として探し回った
Searching around after losing a shoe in the bushes,
何があっても僕らはきっとうまくいくと
Laughing innocently, 'No matter what happens,
無邪気に笑えた日々を覚えている
we'll surely be fine,' I remember those days.
どれだけ無残に傷付くことも終わらない
However brutally we get hurt, the endless days,
毎日日に花束を くだらない面影を追いかけ
A bouquet to each day, chasing after silly memories,
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, still sing, still sing.
朝日が昇る前の欠けた月を
The waning moon before the sun rises,
君もどこかで見てるのかな
I wonder if you're looking at it somewhere too.
なぜか訳もないのに胸が痛くて 滲む面影色
For no reason at all, my chest aches, blurry faces.
今更悲しいと叫ぶには
Now, to scream that I'm sad,
あまりに全てが遅すぎたかな
is perhaps all too late for everything.
もう一度初めから歩けるなら
If I could walk from the beginning once more,
すれ違うように君に会いたい
I'd want to meet you as we pass by.
どれだけ背丈が変わろうとも 変わらない
No matter how much our heights may change,
何かがありますように
I hope something remains unchanging.
くだらない面影に励まされ
Encouraged by silly memories,
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, still sing, still sing.
「午前5時半に、朝日を見に行こう。」
"At 5:30 AM, let's go see the sunrise."
あいつが突然切り出した
That person suddenly brought it up
僕は戸惑って少し嫌がって
I was hesitant and a little reluctant
でも君が「行こう？」って言うもんだからさ
But you said "Shall we go?", so...
眠い目を擦り海へ向かう
Rubbing my sleep-heavy eyes, I head toward the sea
暗がりの向こう君が来る
Beyond the darkness, you are coming
肝心のあいつはまだ来ない
The important person still hasn't arrived
僕ら二人ぼっちこのままで
Just the two of us, like this
もうあなたから愛されることも
I’m no longer loved by you,
必要とされることもない
And you don’t need me anymore.
そして私はこうして一人ぼっちで
And so I feel like I’m all alone.
あの時あなたは何て言ったの?
What did you say to me then?
届かない言葉は宙を舞う
Before reaching me, those words dance in the air.
わかってるのに今日もしてしまう
Although I know this very well, today again
叶わぬ願いごとを
I make a wish, which will never come true.
離さないで ぎゅっと手を握っていて
Don’t let me go, hold my hand tight...
あなたと二人 続くと言って
Tell me that you and I will stay together...
繋いだその手は温かくて
Your hand, holding mine, was so warm and tender!
優しかった
That was so warm and tender.
あなたはいつもそうやって私を
You were always like that,
怒らせて最後に泣かすんだもんね
Making me angry and in the end making me cry.
だけど後になって
But then you apologized...
ごめんねっていうその顔 好きだった
I loved your face at that moment.
離さないで ぎゅっと そう思いきっり
Don’t let me go, hug me with all your might...
あなたの腕の中にいたい
I want to stay in your arms...
二人でおでこをあわせながら眠るの
And we’ll fall asleep together, touching foreheads!
もう二度とは会えないってことを知っていたの?
Did you know that we could never meet again?
離さないで ぎゅっと あなたが好き
Don’t let me go, because I love you so much...
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの
You will never smile at me again...
あなたの温もりが消えいってしまう前に
So, before your warmth fades,
抱きしめて
hug me!
離さないで ぎゅっと そう思いきっり
Don’t let me go, hug me with all your might...
あなたの腕の中にいたい
I want to stay in your arms...
二人でおでこをあわせながら眠るの
And we’ll fall asleep together, touching foreheads!
もう二度とは会えないってことを知っていたの?
Did you know that we could never meet again?
離さないで ぎゅっと あなたが好き
Don’t let me go, because I love you so much...
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの
You will never smile at me again...
離さないで ぎゅっと あなたが好き
Don’t let me go, because I love you so much...
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの
You will never smile at me again...
あなたの温もりが消えいってしまう前に
So, before your warmth fades,
抱きしめて
hug me tight...
どこかで鐘が鳴って
Somewhere a bell rings,
らしからない言葉が浮かんできて
and words not like me come to mind,
寒さが心地よくて
the cold feels so comforting,
なんで恋なんかしてんだろ
why am I falling in love?
聖夜なんだと繰り返す歌と
A song repeating that it's Christmas Eve,
わざとらしくきらめく街のせいかな
and the streets glittering so artificially...
会いたいと思う回数が
The number of times I want to see you,
会えないと痛いこの胸が
and this chest aching when I can't meet you
君のことどう思うか 教えようとしている
are trying to tell me what I think about you.
いいよ そんなこと自分でも分かっているよ
Fine, I know that myself already,
サンタとやらに関いても仕方ないよな
and it's no use asking Santa or anything.
できれば横にいて欲しくて どこにも行って欲しくなくて
If possible, I want you right by my side, not going anywhere,
僕のことだけをずっと考えていてほしい
and wanting you to think only of me all the time.
でもこんなこと伝えたら格好悪いし
But if I told you something like this, it would be uncool,
長くなるだけだからまとめるよ
so since it'd just get long, I'll sum it up:
君が好きだ
I like you.
はしゃぐ恋人たちは
The excited lovers
トナカイのツノなんか生やして
growing reindeer antlers,
よく人前で出来るな
how can they do that in public?
いや羨ましくなんてないけど
No, it's not like I'm envious, but...
君が喜ぶプレゼントってなんだろう
What kind of present would make you happy?
僕だけがあげられるものってなんだろう
What is something only I can give you?
大好きだと言った返事が 思っていたのとは違って
Even if your reply to "I love you" is different from what I expected,
それだけで嫌いになんてなれやしないから
I couldn't possibly start hating you just because of that.
星に願いをなんてさ 柄じゃないけど
Wishing upon a star, it's not really my style, but
結局君じゃないと嫌なんだって見上げているんだ
in the end, I know I don't want anyone else but you, so I'm looking up at the sky.
あの時君に出会って ただそれだけで
Meeting you back then, that alone
自分も知らなかった自分が 次から次に
created parts of myself I never even knew, one after another.
会いたいと毎日思ってて
I want to see you every day,
それを君に知ってほしくて
I want you to know that,
すれ違う人混みに君を探している
and I'm searching for you in the passing crowd.
こんな日は他の誰かと笑っているのかな
On a day like this, are you smiling with someone else?
胸の奥の奥が苦しくなる
The deep inside of my chest becomes painful.
「くだらないテレビを早速すぐ消して勉強し なさい」って
"Turn off the boring television right away and study,"
ホントやんなっちゃうぜ yeah
seriously, I'm so sick of it, yeah.
将来考えてねむくなっちゃうパラダイス
Thinking about the future makes me sleepy in paradise.
どっかに飛んでいったあのときの感情
The emotions of that time flew away somewhere.
夏は通り過ぎていく消えそうなサマーデイズ
Summer passes by, summer days that seem to fade.
僕等何かを始めよう
Let's start something.
たかが運命なんてもんを変えていける気がするんだ
I feel like fate is something we can change.
語り合った未来だって忘れかけそうになっていた
Even the future we talked about was about to be forgotten,
純粋なこころは変わっていないのに
even though my pure heart hasn't changed.
長くなるだけだからまとめるよ
Since it'll just get long, I'll sum it up:
君が好きだ
I love you.
聞こえるまで何度だって言うよ
I'll say it as many times as it takes until you can hear it:
君が好きだ
I love you.
はーい、というわけでクリスマス衣装に着替えて、
Hii, and so we changed into our Christmas outfits,
ボクらママさんのクリスマスソングは、お届けしました！
and delivered Momosuzu Mama's Christmas song!
歌っちゃった！
We sang it!
はーい！
Hii!
なんか...
Somehow...
なんで笑ってるの？
Why are you laughing?
なんかさぁ...
Well, you know...
とわさまがさ、リハのときさ、
Towa-sama, during rehearsal,
なんか噛まなかった？そんなことなかった？
didn't she stumble? Or did she not?
全然噛まなかった！
I didn't stumble at all!
いや、すごいさ、マジで直ぐ表情にで...
No, amazingly, it showed right on your face...
このあと？
After this?
みんなも、もしかして見えちゃった？
Did everyone perhaps see it too?
とわさまのが見えちゃったんじゃないの？一瞬。
Didn't Towa-sama's show? Just for a second.
ちょっとね、侵入してる警石がありまして来るのも、
Well, there was an intruder guard-stone arriving,
ちょっと面白かったの。堪えるの必死だった。
and it was kinda funny. It took everything I had to hold back.
笑い耐えた？
You held back your laughter?
はーい、じゃあここまでの曲の話をしていきたいと思います！
Hii, well then, let's talk about the songs up to this point!
まずは、ロキ、ネネとトワが出ましたね。
First, Loki, Nene and Towa performed.
もう、すっごい自由にやってた。
Man, they were doing whatever they wanted.
元気良くね、歌いました。私、こう踊りました。練習と全然違うことしてました。
We sang energetically. I danced like this. I did things totally different from practice.
ぐるぐるしてましたね。ぐるぐるしてあった。
You were spinning around. You spun around.
はい、そして次、えーすいちゃんとトワでハイドアンド・シーク、歌いました！歌いました！よかったよ。
Yes, and next, uh, Suisei and Towa sang Hide and Seek! We sang it! It was great.
お、これ。お、これね。いって、いって、酔ったらどうする？酔ったら？酔よりないよりな...
Oh, this. Oh, this right here. Say, say, what if you get drunk? If you get drunk? If you're not drunker...
あ、ち、ち、ち、ちょっと！
Ah, wai-, wai-, wai-, wait!
カメラ...カメラちょっと、こっちだけ、こっちだけハイドアンドシークなんですけれども、
Camera... camera, just this way, just this way is Hide and Seek, but...
はい、近日動画がアップされます！
Yes, a video will be uploaded soon!
すごい！そうなんですよ！
Amazing! That's right!
ちょっとね、この日目掛けて頑張って作ってましたね。はい、そうなんです。
We worked hard targeting this day. Yes, that's right.
とわのチャンネルでアップする予定ですので、みんなぜひぜひ楽しみに待ってチェックしておいてくれたら嬉しいな。
It's scheduled to be uploaded on Towa's channel, so everyone please look forward to it and check it out!
楽しみにしててください！
Please look forward to it!
そして、ねねすいのデパーチャーズ、あなたに贈る愛の歌。どうだった？切ない、かわいいみたいな感じじゃなかった？
And then, NeneSui's Departures, a song of love dedicated to you. How was it? Wasn't it like bittersweet and cute?
いや、たっきゃ...よかった！よかったよね！よかった！すごい！
Man, it was high-spirited... great! It was great, right? Great! Amazing!
でも、最後のとこめっちゃすごいと思った本当は。
But I thought the very end part was really amazing, honestly.
いやでもねねっちもすごい頑張って、ね、一緒に歌ってたの。ねねっちめちゃ必死だったからさ。
Well, but Nenechi worked really hard too, singing along with me. Nenechi was super desperate, you know.
でさ、私ね、この、このあとクリスマスソング歌うじゃないですか。
And you know, I, like, after this we sing a Christmas song, right?
で、ここで気づいたんですよ。クリスマスソング歌いながら私気づいたんですけど、今日バラばっかり歌ってる。
And I realized right here. While singing the Christmas song, I realized, today we're only singing rose songs.
確かに！
True!
確かに！でしょ？でもクリスマっぽいよね、なんか。バラード確か。
True! Right? But it feels Christmasy, somehow. Ballads, for sure.
今日はね、あのセットリストはクリスマっぽいやつを選んできたんで、みんなさ。
Today, you know, we chose a setlist that felt Christmasy, so everyone...
泣いたって、泣いたって！泣いたの？
Cried, you cried! You cried?
助かる！涙を助かる！本当にそうだった。
Saves me! Tears saved me! It really was like that.
クリスマスソングもね、みんなでね、はい、はい、はい、はいってね。
The Christmas song too, everyone together, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, like that.
え、これなんとね、えっと、始ま、始まる前のリハのときに、ジャンケンをして勝った人がセンターで。
Uh, and this, you know, during the rehearsal before it started, we played rock-paper-scissors and the winner gets the center.
すいちゃんが勝ったんだよね。そうそう、じゃんけんで勝って、よっしゃつって。
Suisei won, right? Yeah, yeah, winning rock-paper-scissors, saying "Yosha!" and got center.
ちょっとあの、だいふんぺらぺら...あ、そうごめん、すいません、すいません。
Wait, uh, daifun perapera... Ah, right sorry, excuse me, excuse me.
はい、そして次でね、なんとあの、1時間の最後の曲になってしまうんですが！
Yes, and next, amazingly, it's going to be the final song of the one hour!
ここで告知があります！ちょっとお二人は、がやおねがいします。
Here we have an announcement! Uh, you two, please get hyped.
はーい！
Hi!
えっちゃ、こちらどーん！
Nene-chi, right here, ta-da!
ももすずねね80万人記念のグッズが発売になります！
Momosuzu Nene's 800k subscriber merch is going on sale!
イエーイ！
Yay!
二人ともごめんねこんな巻き込んじゃって！
Sorry for dragging you two into this!
よっ、よっ！
Yo, yo!
えと、気になる内容なんですけど、こちらです！
Um, if you're curious about what's inside, here it is!
ももすずねねのアクリルキーホルダーと、ねっこ連結アクリルチャーム3種セット、そしてネネシールネネアザラシのサーモボトルだが、水筒が出ます！
Momosuzu Nene's acrylic keychain, the Nekko connected acrylic charm 3-piece set, and the Nene Seal & Nene-azarashi thermo bottle, a water bottle!
ななんと全部ねねが描き下ろししました！
And guess what? Nene drew all of them herself!
えらちー！
Good job, me!
デザインもねね！
The designs are all Nene too!
自分自身で自己プロデュースしたグッズが出ます！
Merchandise that I self-produced is coming out!
それぞれ単品でも購入できるし、フルセットには複製箔押しのメッセージ＆サイン入りのポストカードが特典でついてくるので、もうカートオープンしてるのでよかったらね、更新したら明日にURLが出ると思うので、
You can buy them individually, but the full set comes with a special postcard featuring a replicated hot-stamped message and signature! The cart is already open, so once it updates tomorrow a URL should be out,
皆さんよくチェックしてください！
so please make sure to check it out!
チェック、チェック！
Check, check!
みんなのおかげでね、もう85万人の方が近くなったんですけど、感謝とお礼の気持ちを込めて全部自分でデザインして描き下ろししたのでよかったらお手にとっていただけると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
Thanks to everyone, we're getting close to 850k subscribers! I designed and drew everything myself with gratitude, so I'd be happy if you could pick them up! Thank you so much!
いやあちょっとね、今日最初は機材トラブルでちょっと遅れちゃったんですけど、
Man, we had some equipment trouble at the very beginning today and got a little late,
まあすごいねねはね、本当に二人を呼んでよかったと思いました今日は。
but I really felt so glad I invited these two today.
本当に？
Really?
うん、楽しかったよ、今日。本当に？
Yeah, it was fun today. Really?
いやでもダンスの練習のときとかずっとなおしかった。楽しかった！
Yeah, but dance practice and stuff was always so fun. So fun!
本当に楽しかった！
Really fun!
先生もね見てくれてるらしいから、せんせー！ありがとうございました！ねねミスったよ！
Sensei is apparently watching too, so Sensei! Thank you very much! Nene messed up!
ねねちさ、なんかさ、あのずっとさ、えーとか言いながら踊ってたでしょ？
Nene-chi, you were dancing the whole time saying things like "Eh...", right?
そう、レッスンのとき間違えると悲鳴が出ちゃうんだよねねね！もうね録画したビデオにのこったよ！
Yeah, if you make a mistake during practice you let out a scream! It's recorded on video!
本当だ！
For real!
はいそれでは、えーそろそろ最後の曲に行きましょうか皆さん！はい！じゃあちょっと立ち位置ついて、じゃあ先生見てて、絶対に次は間違いないから！
All right then, let's move on to the final song, everyone! Yeah! Let's get into position. Sensei, watch us, we definitely won't make mistakes this time!
それでは最後の曲です！聞いてください！せーの！
And now, it's the final song! Please listen! Ready, set!
スノーハレーション！
Snow halation!
不思議だね 今の気持ち
Isn't it strange, how we feel right now?
空から降ってきたみたい
It's almost like it fell from the sky
特別な季節の色が とめきを見せるよ
The hues of this special time of year show the fluttering of our hearts
初めて出会った時から
Ever since we first met
予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
The melody of my heart's been going crazy over a hunch
とめられないとまらない な・ぜ
Why can't I stop it, won't it stop?
届けて
Let's name this pain
切なさには名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
"Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで待てずに
Don't wait until your feelings pile up
悔しいけど好きって純情
It's frustrating but it's pure love
微熱の中ためらってもだめだね
In the midst of hesitation, you can't hold back
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Approve the courage to jump in, the start is near!!
音もなく 気配もなく
Without a sound or a sign
静かに運命は変わる
Our fate quietly changes
これからの未来に胸の 鼓動が早くなる
The excitement in our chests quickens for the future
例えば困ったときには すぐに駆けつけて抱きしめたくて
If you're ever in a bind, I wanna rush over and hold you
どこにいてもどこでも Fly high
Wherever you are, we can fly high anywhere
急いで いつの間にか大きくなりすぎた“True emotion”
Hurry, before you know it, "True emotion" has grown too big
夢だけみてる柄じゃないよ
It hurts to think I might just be dreaming
恋人は君って言いたい
I wanna call you sweetheart
優しい目が とまどってる イヤだよ
Your kind eyes confuse me, stop it!
ding-dong 賑やかな鐘の音に
ding-dong, to the sound of lively bells
ding-dong リンクする鼓動
ding-dong, heartbeats linking together
胸いっぱいに入れ込んできた
Taking in a chest full of excitement
12月のモード
The December mood
ずっと楽しみにしてたから
I've been looking forward to this all along
ちょっと緊張気味かも
Maybe I'm a little nervous
待ち合わせまであともう少し
Just a little more until we meet up
可愛くなれ、わたし
Be cute, myself
いつもよりウンとオシャレして
Dressing up a bit more stylishly than usual
やっぱり過剰はヤメにした
Decided that going overboard was a no-go
コーデの主役はさりげなく
The star of the outfit, casually
今日のための
For today
よそ行きルージュ for you
My going-out rouge for you
今夜メリー・メリー・クリスマス！
Tonight is a merry, merry Christmas!
街中が恋のステージ
The whole town is a stage for romance
イルミネーションの下で
Under the illuminations
とびっきりの二人になれるね
We can be an amazing couple
一年一度の特別な夜ははじまる
The once-a-year special night begins
いっぱい思い出作りたい
I want to make so many memories
待ちわびた
Waiting eagerly for this
holy date
ゆうべなかなか眠れなくて
Couldn't sleep well last night
なんか実感しちゃった
I kind of realized it
笑えるくらい大好きなこと
Something I love so much it makes me smile
今日も伝えさせて
Let me convey it today too
どんな人混みの中だって
No matter how crowded it is
すぐお互い見つけ合える
We can find each other right away
みんな誰かの大事なひと
Everyone is someone's precious person
キミにも感じてほしいな
I want you to feel that too
love you
今夜メリー・メリー・クリスマス！
Tonight is a merry, merry Christmas!
街中が恋のストーリー
The whole town is a love story
瞳の真ん中いつも
Right in the center of my eyes, always
キラキラなキミを映してる
Reflecting sparkling you
一年一度の特別な夜にはしゃこう
Let's get excited on this once-a-year special night
いっぱい笑顔にしたいんだ
I want to make you smile so much
まかせてね
Leave it to me
holy date
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, 贈ろう
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, let's give it
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, 受け取って
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, accept it
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, ありがとう
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, thank you
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, もらったよ
love sha-la-la-la, love and joy, I received it
いつか大人になって
Someday when we grow up
思い出す瞬間も
Even the moments we remember
会いに来てくれてありがとう！！楽しんでくれたかなぁ～ ねね
Thank you for coming to meet us!! Did you enjoy it? Nene
Merry Christmas トワ様からのプレゼント♡ Towa
Merry Christmas: A present from Towa-sama ♡ Towa
クリスマス・イブ・イブ・イブを一緒にすごせてよかったよ☆ Suisei
I'm glad we could spend Christmas Eve-Eve-Eve together☆ Suisei